本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：王小麦  包包  七个柚子酱  菲力  吃货丁小七
翻译：面条打包子  MythCreator  姚小事儿  幸田实果子
翻译：guzppi  喵喵阿飘  CS小明漫画家  某羽
时间轴：阿包  新月  kitty  贝贝
校对：某羽  王小麦
后期：8T  MythCreator  总监：王小麦
真探
前情提要
2002年出了些事
Something went down, 2002.
你前夫的搭档
Your ex-husband's partner,
拉斯丁·科尔
Rustin Cohle.
我认识的拉斯特是个好人
I knew Rust to be a good man,
所以我不知道我有什么好说的
so I can't imagine what I can offer.
我是唯一一个支持你的人
I'm the only one ever took up for you.
不  老弟  没有我
No, buddy, without me...
也不会有你
there is no you.
那个带疤的
The man
男人
with the scars,
他逼着我看
he made me watch
他对比利做的一切
what he did to Billy.
我们为什么谈起这个呢
What's this all about now?
因为死了女人和儿童
Dead women and children.
你的搭档  他骚扰了比利·李·塔特尔
Your partner here, he braced Billy Lee Tuttle.
这就是我所说的
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
如果他因为我们的谈话而大发雷霆
If he was pissed off after the conversation we had,
那就说明我的调查方向是对的
then I am on to something.
我真的很想见你
I really wanted to see you.
请稍等
我看到你手机上的照片了
I saw the pictures on your phone.
我控制不了某些疯婆子给我发
I cannot help it if some crazy bitch sent--
我和别人上床了
I slept with someone.
拉斯特
It was Rust.
我辞职
I quit.
你当真吗
You serious?
我觉得也许我们该谈谈
Thought maybe we should talk.
行  你带路
Sure. I'll follow you.
真探
第一季第七集
你看起来还不错
You look like you're doing all right.
时光老人对我们自有一套
Father Time has his way with us all.
你看起来到像是惹毛他了
Looks like you must have pissed him off.
我们来这儿要干嘛
Why we here?
我对州警察部门在问的事
I got a thing
有点想法
the State PD's asking about.
查尔斯湖谋杀案
The Lake Charles murder.
都这个时候了
I mean, shouldn't it have been in the paper
难道不是应该已经结案了吗
to draw a line somewhere by now?
我们不能相信他们
I mean, we can't trust them.
如果他们连这种事都想掩盖
And, I mean, if they're gonna cover something like that up,
谁知道他们还掩盖了什么事
who knows what else they've covered up?
你怎么认为
What you think?
我认为你看起来很不健康
I think you don't look particularly healthy.
你的说话方式
Listening to you talk,
你的眼睛  看起来
your eyes, you seem
你已经到极限了  拉斯特
kind of brittle, Rust.
过去十年里大多数时间我都烂醉如泥
Most of the last decade I spent stone-drunk.
还能动弹  但是影响很大
Functional, but hammered.
回阿拉斯加待了八年
Went back to Alaska,
打渔  调酒
spent 8 years working fishing boats, bars.
-我还以为你不喜欢天冷  -我讨厌天冷
- Oh, I thought you didn't like the cold. - I hate it.
2010年
And then I come back here
我第一次回来路易斯安那
to Louisiana for the first time in 2010.
为什么回来
And why is that?
和我现在坐在你对面的原因一样
The same reason I'm sitting across the table from you now.
男人不会忘了他欠得债
A man remembers his debts.
我不喜欢细数过去
I don't dwell on the past.
那感觉一定很好
Well, it must be nice.
不管你认为你欠我什么  我都不感兴趣
I'm not interested in whatever it is you think you owe me.
我不欠你什么
Oh, I don't owe you.
而是我们有事没做完
We left something undone.
我们必须做完
We got to fix it,
我这两年一直在忙这事
and I've been working on this for two years.
我  一个人
Me, myself.
从来没找过你  从来没麻烦过你
Never called you, I never bothered you with it--
是啊  你为什么会找我  操  你都做了些什么
Yeah, why would you? Shit, man, what did you do?
你疏远你生命中的每个人
Alienate every other person in your life,
然后最终又回来找我
and then finally you came back to me in the rotation?
不是我要指责什么
You know, not for nothing,
但是如果你当时没干掉勒杜
but if you wouldn't have clipped Ledoux back then,
也许我们已经把整件事弄清楚了
we might have got the whole fucking story out of him.
我把酒喝完就走
You know, I think I'm gonna finish this beer and say so long.
我最近已经不怎么喝酒了
Now, I'm not much of a drinker nowadays.
事实上  遇到你之前我已经三周没喝了
In fact, I hadn't had a drop in 3 weeks till I ran into you.
我不需要你喝酒  小马
Well, I don't need you to drink, Marty.
-我需要你帮我  -我为什么要帮你
- I need you to help me. - Why would I?
他们说你无法证明自己在哪里
They say you can't account for your time.
并且有目击证人看到你在
They got eyewitnesses placing you
查尔斯湖犯罪现场出现
at the Lake Charles crime scene.
你有个仓库却不肯让他们查看
You got some storage shed that you won't let them look at.
-没错  -为什么不
- That's right. - Why not?
为什么不跟他们合作  你是清白的
Why not shoot straight with them? You're innocent.
别让他们再浪费时间了
Help them stop wasting their time.
什么时候开始
Fucking since when did guilt
由州警察部门决定谁清白谁有罪了
and innocence define the State PD, huh?
去他妈的
Come the fuck on.
我不知道这事铺得有多大
Now, I don't know the sprawl of this thing, all right?
我所调查的那些人  都要完了
The people I'm after, they're all fucking over.
他们牵涉进了很多事
They're in a lot of different things,
也牵扯出了很多人
pieces, family trees.
只有让你亲眼看到
The only way for you to understand
你才会明白我在说什么
what I'm on to here is for me to show you.
你得来看看我查出了什么
You got to come see what I got.
不
No. You know what?
你还没搞清楚  拉斯特
I don't think I've been very clear with you, Rust.
如果你溺水了
If you were drowning,
我会扔副杠铃帮你沉下去
I'd throw you a fucking barbell.
我为什么要帮你
Why would I ever help you?
因为你有债要还
Because you have a debt.
你真是脑子有问题
You got some fucking sack.
你什么意思  我有什么债要还
What's that mean, I have a debt, huh?
95年发生的那事
Means the way shit went down in '95,
你也有责任  伙计
this is on you, too, buddy.
你有什么要给我看的
What do you got to show me?
你带了什么
What you packing?
点38手枪
.38.
空尖弹
Hollow-point?
是的
Yeah.
够用了
That'd do it.
小心点总不是坏事
You never be too careful.
黄袍国王  伤疤男  卡寇莎
好了
All right.
记住  没有实物证据
Remember, there was no physical evidence
可以将朵拉·兰和勒杜森林里的小屋联系起来
connecting Dora Lange to Ledoux's place out in the woods,
说明那里也许不是案发现场
meaning it probably didn't happen out there.
从来没人提过这事
Nobody was in a hurry to bring that up.
第二  女人和小孩失踪了
Two--women and children gone missing,
全部发生在塔特尔教会思源计划资助的学校
all taken from areas within a 10-mile radius
周围16公里范围之内
of schools that were funded by Tuttle's Wellspring initiative.
我们要找到联系
We establish a connection.
谁有问题  谁是干净的
Who's in, who's out, you know?
州里其他地区失踪人数相近吗
I mean, do people disappear
失踪人数相近吗
in equal numbers in other parts of the state?
-一共有多少所学校  -14所
- How many schools were there? - 14.
我大体上查过了
Now, I've covered a surface area.
我查了州里离家出走
I pulled runaways in state
和失踪人员清单  你会注意到
and missing persons, and if you'll notice,
沿河区域的数字是其他地区的两倍
there's twice as many along the bayous.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why.
我们得好好调查一下这为什么
Hell, someone should do a study as to why.
你现在只是在列数字
Well, now you're just throwing up stats.
为什么塔特尔会对兰的案子这么感兴趣
Why was Tuttle so interested in the Lange case, huh?
还记得查理·兰说的勒杜跟他说过的话吗
Remember Charlie Lange said what Ledoux told him?
他说有一群人  他们拿人做祭品
Said there's a group of men, sacrifices.
我认为塔特尔认出了那个场景
Well, I think Tuttle recognized the scene.
所以他才会那么快就赶来
That's why he came down
还带了个特别小组
there jiminy quick with a fucking task force,
所以我02年和他谈过之后他才会离开
and that's why he tripped out when I talked to him in '02.
那到底发生了什么
OK, so what happened to him?
你这里这些东西
I mean, I'm looking around here,
没有任何一件可以证明
and I don't see or hear anything
你不是在妄加猜测
that doesn't make this all conjectural.
1988年
1988.
塔特尔资助的一家幼儿园
Accusations of child molestation
被指控有猥亵儿童的行为
at a preschool funded by Tuttle.
那所幼儿园叫牧羊人之家
Name of that school is Shepherd's Flock.
当时被关闭了  两年后在鹈鹕岛重新开张
It shuts down, reopens two years later on Pelican Island
名字叫光明之路学院
under the name Light of the Way Academy,
莉安·奥利弗就在那里上的学
where Rianne Olivier went.
我弄到了登记表  班上有16个孩子
And I got an enrollment list-- 16 kids in the class.
其中一个后来在新奥尔良
One of them turned out to be a young man who'd just showed up
因为卖淫而受过审
for solicitation in New Orleans.
那是2010年
Now, this is 2010.
他叫托比·伯莱尔
His name is Toby Boelert.
化名强尼·乔妮
Goes by the name of Johnny Joanie.
牧羊人之家
Shepherd's Flock?
你为什么会问这个地方
Why are you asking me about that place?
那学校关闭之后
You know, after that place shut down,
有很多风言风语
there was a lot of talk going around.
你见过那个牧师吗
You ever see that reverend...
比利·李·塔特尔
Billy Lee Tuttle, around?
应该见过  但是谁记得那么久的事呢
You know, I think so, but who can remember way back?
都是这么回事
That's how it all started.
记性总是先出问题
Memory be fucked.
我决定把那一切都当做是在做梦
I decided it all had to be a dream anyways,
我不记得它
and I don't remember if it...
我们晚上会睡觉
We'd go to sleep,
但是有时我觉得不像是在睡觉
only sometimes I didn't feel like I was asleep.
感觉像是醒着  但是我又一定是在睡觉
I felt like I was still awake, but I must have been asleep
因为我不能动
because I couldn't move.
就像是闭着眼却能看见东西
Just...sort of see under my eyelids.
然后呢
And what?
我不知道
I don't know.
有很多人
There were men...
在拍照
taking pictures.
有时
Sometimes...
会做其他事
other things.
都是些什么人
Who were they?
我不知道
I don't know.
都长着动物脸
They had animal faces.
所以我才决定把这一切当做是做梦
That's why I decided it had to be a dream.
他们都长着动物脸  那一定是在做梦
They had animal faces, well, it had to be a dream.
有其他小孩见过吗
Any other kids see this?
一个小女孩见过
One girl.
我不记得她叫什么名字了
I don't remember her name.
是她先说起来的
She first started talking about it.
她也看到了那些脸
And she seen it, too, the faces.
我不记得她叫什么名字了
I do not remember her name.
玛丽·方特诺特
Marie Fontenot?
也许吧
Maybe.
你见过那些人的真容吗
You ever see any of these men's faces?
见过一次
Once.
他们不是每个人都长着动物脸
They didn't all have animal faces.
有三个年轻人  我不记得是谁了
Three younger men. I don't remember them.
其中一个
Just one.
他嘴唇附近全是伤疤
He had bad scars all around his mouth,
好像下半张脸全被烧毁了
like the bottom half got all burned up.
我把那个人也当做做梦了
I thought that man, he was a dream, too.
不  我不认为那是在做梦
No, I don't think he was a dream.
我糊涂了
I don't understand.
你的意思是
Are you saying that you think
这个假想的杀手
that this hypothetical killer
曾经是个学校教师
was, uh, an old schoolteacher?
或是和州警察部门有关
Or it might what, involve State PD?
老天啊  你怎么了
Goddamn. What happened to you, man?
还记得他吗
Remember him?
记得
Yeah.
那是我们在伊拉斯查的案子
Yeah. You and I were on the case in Erath.
有个女孩说她被一个长着绿耳朵的意面怪
Girl comes forward and says she was chased through the woods
追进了树林
by a spaghetti monster with green ears.
我觉得那就是
Now, I think that this is our man
脸上有伤疤的那个男人
with the scars on his face.
17年前就有三例证明了
We got 3 references 17 years ago: that old
复兴教会的人说有个脸上有疤的高个男子来过
revival church said a tall man with scars came through,
医院里的凯莉·瑞德
Kelly Reider in the hospital,
还有那个妓男  托比
and now this hooker from the quarter--Toby.
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who he is,
我不知道他在哪里  我不知道这些事的源头
I don't know where he is, I don't know where
在哪儿  但是找到他就能解开这一切
this whole thing fucking starts, but it ends with him.
你还记得伊拉斯附近的那个小镇吗
All right, you know the little township down around Erath?
塔特尔家就来自那里
All right, that's where the Tuttle family is from.
那本来只是个藏匿之所
Now, it used to be a pirate hideout,
后来变成了农场之类的
then turned into plantations and whatnot.
那里有乡村风味的狂欢节
Had a very rural sense of Mardi Gras, uh,
骑马  动物面具  诸如此类
you know, the men on horses, animals masks, such.
-惭悔星期二  -没错
- Courir de Mardi Gras. - That's right.
他们每年都会有冬至节
Now, they had an annual winter festival.
在萨特纳里亚尤其盛行
Went heavy on the Saturnalia, a place where
在那里桑泰里厄教和伏都教融合在一起
that Santeria and Voudon all mash together.
看这里
Have a look.
从冬至节
From the winter festival.
眼罩
Blindfold...
鹿角  面具
antlers, mask.
这是卡特里娜飓风之后
I got these from a series an artist did in Kenner,
肯纳的一个艺术家的系列创作之一
right after Katrina.
他说一直看到这些被他称为
Says he kept running across these "stick things,"
"棍子搭成的物品"的东西
as he called them.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
看来我们要找的人在飓风之后"快活"了一阵
Think our man had a real good time after the hurricane--
各种混乱
chaos,
有人失踪  有人离开
people missing, and people gone.
警察走了
Cops gone.
我觉得他有一个好年景
I think he had a real good year.
你要我做什么
What do you need me for?
你在警局有朋友
You got friends on the force.
你有数据库的访问权而我没有
You have access that I don't, databases.
我需要案卷
I need case files.
失踪人口  谋杀案
I need missing persons. I need homicides.
汽车和房屋的所有权转让的档案
I need title transfers, auto and home.
我有一份名单
I got a list of names.
我需要他们的背景调查  税务记录
I'm gonna need background checks, tax records,
任何能让我们抓住勒杜的线索
anything we can get on Ledoux.
天呐  伙计
Jesus Christ, man.
要是州警没有把我扯进查尔斯湖的案子
I wouldn't have called you
我也不会给你打电话
and I wouldn't have fucking bothered you
我不想打扰你
if State wouldn't have pulled me in on this Lake Charles case.
要是你需要帮忙
Well, if you need help,
为什么不把这些给帕帕尼亚和吉尔包
why don't you just give it to Papania and Gilbough?
不  他们只是一枚棋子  自己还没发觉
No, they may be pawns in this thing and not even fucking know it.
-得了吧  -埃迪·塔特尔是这个州的参议员
- Come on. - Look, Eddie Tuttle is the goddamn senator of this state.
已故的比利·李·塔特尔牧师是他的堂亲
The late Reverend Billy Lee Tuttle is his cousin.
我跟你说  这就是家族事务
I'm telling you, it's a fucking family thing.
我跟你说事情不简单就是这意思  小马
That's what I mean when I talk about the sprawl, Marty!
埃迪·塔特尔是查尔斯湖的案子
Eddie Tuttle's the reason
一直没法结案的原因所在
that the Lake Charles thing never made the wire.
伙计  你这里有强有力的证据
Look, man, you have some compelling stuff here
而且你可能真的有些调查方向
and you might have something,
但是...
but...
所有的这些  你所谓的
all this--this--the "sprawl,"
"麻烦事"  我称之为猜想
as you call it, which I would call conjecture,
这个有关塔特尔  州警的破事
this shit about the Tuttles, the State PD.
你知道这听上去多么疯狂
Do you know how fucking crazy that sounds?
就像你孤单一人太久了
It's like you've been alone too long, you know,
你给自己讲了这个故事
like you maybe told yourself this story
还不停地喝酒  直到你自己相信了它
and kept drinking until you believed it.
小马...
Marty...
我曾花了很久来确认这些是否只是我的幻想
I had my time where I wondered if this was all in my head.
那都是过去的事了
That time passed.
真的吗
Really?
比利·李·塔特尔怎么了
What happened to Billy Lee Tuttle?
这有些东西你得看看
There's something you're gonna have to look at.
不看没法理解
No other way around it.
你还喝清咖吗
You still take your coffee black?
绿茶  要是你有的话
Oh, uh, green tea, if you have it.
我一直在努力戒咖啡
I've been trying to stay away from coffee,
稍微健康一点
you know, a little bit healthier.
那梅斯从芝加哥回来了吗
So, Mace--is she, uh, back from Chicago yet?
嗯  三个月前回的
Mm-hmm, 3 months ago.
三个月
3 months.
那是什么  那个…
Uh...and what was it, that--
美利坚志愿团
Americorps.
就是教书
Teaching.
奥德丽  她怎么样了
And Audrey, how--how's she?
她现在很好
She's fine, at the moment.
她有时会自己决定不吃药
She sometimes decides she doesn't need her meds.
我喜欢她男朋友
I like her boyfriend.
他很小心地照顾着她
He watches out for her.
她在新奥尔良开了场艺术展
She had an art show in New Orleans,
卖了几幅画
sold some paintings.
不错啊  那很好
Oh, that's good. That's great.
我也该买一幅
I should buy one,
如果我买得起的话
I mean, if I can afford it.
我来这是因为…
So the reason I, uh...
就像我在电话里说的
I mean, like I said on the phone, I...
我想问你几个关于那些警察的问题
I want to ask you about those cops.
他们只是想知道你和拉斯特的事
They just wanted to know about you and Rust.
主要是拉斯特
Mostly Rust.
他们想知道
They wanted to know about
你们02年那场架
the fight in '02.
你告诉他们了吗
Mmm, did you tell them?
没有
No...
但他们觉得拉斯特做了什么
but they think Rust did something.
我知道
I know.
他没有
He didn't.
我也觉得他没有
I didn't think he did.
你跟他…谈过吗
Have you... talked to him?
没  那之后就没有
No, not since.
你呢
Have you?
谈过  在他们把我带去问话之后
Yeah, I mean, after they brought me in.
我们谈过
Yeah.
他怎么样了
How is he?
变了  又没变
Different, same.
他很久以来日子都不好过
I mean, he's lived rough for a long time now.
他好像一直是这样
He always did, it seemed like.
这事对他影响很大
Taken a toll.
他需要我的帮助
He needs my help.
你会帮他吗
Are you gonna help him?
会
Yes.
为什么
Why?
我必须帮
I have to.
是怎么回事  警察觉得他干了什么
Well, what is it? What do the police think he did?
我不能说  这是私家侦探的规定
I can't talk about that. It's PI stuff.
他雇了我的事务所  我雇了他
He's hiring the firm, I'm hiring him.
一直以来  你们俩
All this time, you two,
就这样而已了吗
and just-- just like that?
我被他说服了
Oh, I took some convincing.
我看着比利的眼睛
I looked in Billy's eyes.
黄袍国王  卡寇莎
他也看着我的眼睛
He looked in mine.
他停了我的职
He got me suspended.
比利·李·塔特尔现在在路易斯安那州有三栋房子
Now, Billy Lee Tuttle owns 3 houses in Louisiana.
一栋在薛夫波特  一栋在巴吞鲁日
One in Shreveport, one in Baton Rouge,
还有一栋在新奥尔良
one in New Orleans.
弗罗里达州还有一栋
Also one in Florida.
我一直等到他们部门去春游  10年...
I waited till he went on his spring ministry tour, 2010--
听着  拉斯特  我改主意了
Look, Rust, I changed my mind.
我不想听你都干了什么
If you did something, I don't want to hear about it.
还记得我说过我抢劫的事吗
Remember I told you about my stint in robbery?
我可是撬锁溜门的好手
I make a pretty ace B&E man.
我观察了他的房子好几周
Now, I staked his places out for weeks.
弄清摄像头位置和保安的巡逻规律
Checked surveillance, map security.
我找到了切入口
I found ingresses.
你再看我
Now, here I am, you know.
我的人生就是不断扩大的一塌糊涂
My whole life is just one expanding, circular fuck-up
我觉得犯下非法入室罪
and I think it's about to close out
日子也就到头了
with me getting clipped in a home invasion.
我是说
I mean, what I'm saying is
我知道自己可能疯了
I was aware that I might have lost my mind.
但搜完他第二处住宅后
But after the second home...
这种疑虑消失了
doubt got taken behind the woodshed and put down.
因为他并没有报案说巴吞鲁日的房子被盗
Notice he never reported the Baton Rouge break-in,
只说了薛夫波特的房子
just the Shreveport house.
在那里的保险箱里找到了那些
Found those in the safe there.
那些纸已经保存了15年以上了
Paper stock's over 15 years old.
见鬼
Goddamn it.
还有这些  要是不搞清楚
These... they aren't as bad
你根本意识不到他们的邪恶
if you don't know what you're looking at.
他妈的
Motherfuck.
还有
And...
有一卷录像带
there's a videotape.
看看吧
Take a look.
不
No!
天哪
God!
上帝啊
Jesus!
操
Fuck!
你全看完了
You watch all of that?
是
Yeah.
我得看有没有人摘下过面具
Yeah, I had to, see if any of the men took off their mask.
没人摘过
None did.
操
Oh, fuck.
我不会移开视线
I won't avert my eyes.
这次不会
Not again.
天哪
Jesus Christ.
那个小姑娘是玛丽·方特诺特
That little girl is Marie Fontenot.
是你杀了塔特尔吗
Did you kill Tuttle?
不是
No.
我猜
I assume that
他觉得自己会被勒索
he was thinking he was gonna be blackmailed.
而有人发现发现  在他来得及转移前
And I think some people took him out after they found out
保险箱里东西不见了  就杀了他
what was taken from the safe, before he had a chance to.
我该怎么帮你
What...can I do to help?
我们从所有跟朵拉·兰有关的东西开始查
We start by pulling everything there is on Dora Lange.
我弄了一个名单
And I got names,
名单上是她家人以及塔特尔的教友
I got family members, Tuttle connections.
我们还需要所有跟
Any information that we can get
雷吉或者德沃尔·勒杜有关的信息
on Reggie or Dewall Ledoux.
我们可以在你公司外面碰头
All right, we can coordinate out of your offices
如果你乐意
if you want.
你无权保管那个
You shouldn't have that.
没人有权保管
Nobody should have this.
你一切都好我跟高兴  玛姬
I'm glad that you're doing good, Maggie.
好像所有人都很幸福
It seems like everybody's happy, you know.
挺  咳  挺好的
It's...ahem. It's good to see.
谢谢
Thank you
你做的一切
for everything.
我两年多没见过你了  小马
I haven't seen you in over two years, Marty.
你是来说再见的吗
Did you come here to say good-bye?
谢谢你  玛姬
Thank you, Maggie.
真心的
I mean that.
哈特调查中心
不会有太多人
There's not gonna be a bunch of people
进出这里  对吧
coming in and out of this place, is there?
你觉得呢  拉斯特
What do you think, Rust?
实际上我们要做的就是确认身份和定位
Practical terms, we're doing an identify and locate.
我现在已经订不起
Now, I can't afford to subscribe to all
以前用的那些数据库了
the databases that I used to,
不过我还有能查机动车记录的
but I got Auto Track XP
XP版自动追踪
for motor vehicle records.
我还有QI国家人口检索的
I got Flat Rate Info
所有平价信息
for the QI National People Locator,
当然都是公开的信息
public records, of course.
好吧
All right.
听起来不错
That sounds good.
你这些年过得怎么样
How you been? Ahem.
除了工作之外
You know, besides work,
你都做些什么
what do you do?
不好意思  你以前好像从来没有
I'm sorry, I just-- I don't ever remember you asking me
问过我私人问题
a personal question before.
你也知道的
Uh...you know,
就是让自己一直有点事做
I just stay busy, uh,
钓钓鱼  交交女朋友
fish, girlfriends.
你现在有交往对象吗
You seeing anybody?
不算吧  就约会过几次
Not really. Some dates.
都比较随意
You know, it's all pretty casual.
不过我确实有过一段比较久的关系
I did have something going for a while,
跟一个菲律宾女孩儿  虽然没有结果
this Filipino girl, but that didn't pan out.
生活平静  不在外面鬼混  每天回家
Quiet life. I don't stay out late. I just--I go home.
你呢
You?
我跟你差不多
Ah, I'm about the same.
没有女朋友
No girlfriend.
就是上班下班
Just go to work, go home.
那个02年时跟你交往的女孩怎么样了
How about that girl you were seeing in '02?
跟她发展得怎么样
What ever happened with her?
没交往太长时间
Yeah, that was never gonna last.
就不应该开始
Never should have started.
没错  老天
Yeah. Boy.
她  有点问题
She, uh, she had problems.
你不就喜欢疯狂的女人嘛
Oh, you always liked them crazy.
对  我确实喜欢
Yeah, that I did.
你为什么辞职  小马
Why'd you quit, Marty?
不辞的话你肯定早升官了
Yeah, you could have been boss, you know.
至少是警督  或是警监
LT, at least, Captain.
在你离开后我又干了四年  然后我
I did another 4 years after you left, and I--
可能这工作对我来说太顺其自然了
I guess the job just kind of ran its course with me.
怎么说
How is that?
我以前还想去打棒球  去骑公牛
I was gonna play baseball, ride bulls.
结果就干上了一份
You know, you end up becoming
从未想过的职业
something you never intended.
我猜根本没人能弄明白原因
Uh, I guess you never really even know why.
我说不定还能成为画家
I suppose I could have been a painter,
专画历史事件的
you know, a historian.
旧场景  新细节
Old scenes, new details.
是啊  你经常画画吗
Yeah, yeah. You do much painting?
不画
Nah.
我猜现在再开始已经太晚了
Little late in the game to start something like that, I reckon.
这一辈子连做好一件事都来不及
Life's barely long enough to get good at one thing.
如果活得够长
If that long.
是啊  所以得认真选择要做好的事
Yeah, so be careful what you get good at.
失踪的孩子
对开飞机的黑人该叫什么
What do you call a black man who flies a plane?
我不知道
I don't know.
飞行员  你这个种族歧视的混蛋
Pilot, you racist bastard.
你还想怎么叫他
What else would you call him?
说到这  我上了几门写作课
Well, speaking of, you know, I been taking some writing courses?
说真的
And, uh--no.
我上过  一直时不时地
I have, and I been tinkering around
在修改这份稿子
with this thing off and on.
真实案件
True crime.
那只是体裁  不是标题
And that's the genre, not the title.
-你是认真的  -当然
- You serious? - Yeah.
关于95年还有其他旧案子的
You know, what happened in '95 and some other old cases,
而我需要帮忙  博比
and all I need from you, Bobby,
给我一些以前案件的资料
is some old copies of case files.
你还爱喝单一麦芽威士忌  对吧
You still like your single malt, don't you?
对  没错
Ah, I guess I do.
生意现在这么难做吗
Oh, business gotten so bad
你都被逼当作家了
you got to become a writer?
不  我一直想写书来着
Nope, I've always wanted to do it.
只是以前太忙了
I just never had the time.
说到资料  我可不想碰到傻逼和挫逼
And regards the files, I'd like to avoid Fuck and Suck,
就上周六我碰到的那两人
the two dicks I spent last Saturday with.
帕帕尼亚和吉尔包
Papania and Gilbough.
知道了
I hear ya.
没问题  伙计  如你所愿
'Course, man. Whatever you need.
谢谢你  博比
Appreciate it, Bobby.
不用谢
Not a problem.
很可能是失踪人口
Missing persons, mostly.
也许早在八十年代
Maybe far back as the eighties.
在05年之前的案子卷宗
Well, anything before '05 that never
从不会被官方调查
became part of an official investigation,
肯定不会录入计算机中的
it isn't gonna be in the computers.
你得翻文件了
You're gonna have to sort through the files.
谢谢
Thank you.
找到了点背景线索
Found something, background.
德沃尔·勒杜把一辆卡车的所有权
Dewall Ledoux transferred title
转给一个叫吉米·勒杜的人了
on a truck to a Jimmy Ledoux.
他俩看起来是表亲
Appears like that might be a cousin.
我在白色城堡找到了他
I found him in White Castle.
他开了一家汽车修理店
Owns an auto shop.
好吧
All right.
你找到玛丽·方特诺特的案宗了吗
Did you pull that Marie Fontenot file?
没有
There wasn't one.
文件不见了  正在顺线索调查
Report's gone. Backtracking that.
小马  这位是罗伯特·杜曼
Marty, this is Robert Doumain.
这家店是他的
He owns the place.
生意怎么样
Hey, how's it going?
位置不错
Nice spot.
他不是警察了  罗伯特
He's not a cop no more, Robert.
你有什么讨厌警察的原因吗
You got something against cops?
鲍勃有个孩子
Bob had a little boy.
85年失踪
Been missing since '85.
抱歉
Sorry.
吉米·勒杜生活的挺不错
Jimmy Ledoux came up spotless--
有三个孩子  妻子是老师
3 kids, wife's a teacher.
他是他儿子所在少年橄榄球队的教练
He coaches his boys' pee-wee football team.
有什么联系吗
Any relation?
姓勒杜的人这么多  找点联系实在不难
So many Ledouxs around, I never had to worry about a connection.
当然  是我父亲的远房堂兄弟之类的
But, yeah, my dad's second cousin or something.
我爸对他们一点都不感冒
My pops didn't like them none.
他说他们还没白到可以自称白废物
Said they weren't white enough to be white trash.
这到底是什么事
What's this about, exactly?
有人让我们找到他女儿
Man asked us to locate his daughter.
是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago,
但看起来她或许认识德沃尔
but it looks like she might have known Dewall.
很抱歉听到这个消息
Sorry to hear that.
必须搞清楚他们发生了什么事
Must know what happened to them.
那帮臭傻逼
Sick shits.
爸爸说他们死的太早了
Pop said they died too quick.
你知不知道什么关于这些人的事
Is there anything you
可以告诉我们的
remember that you can tell us about these guys?
他们就是疯子  看人的眼神都透着疯狂
Just they were nuts. Looked at you funky.
雷金经常问起我学校里的女孩子
Reggie was always asking about the girls in my school,
有几次我见到德沃尔的时候
and couple times I saw Dewall,
他都满嘴胡话
he just said kooky stuff.
你有没有看见过
Any chance you ever saw a third man with them,
一个脸下方有大量伤疤的人
a man who had a bunch of scars
和他们在一起
on the bottom of his face?
你这么一说确实
It's weird you say that.
我记得那张脸
I remember that face.
我爸爸有次让他们用我们的猎鹿营地
My pop let them use our deer camp once.
也带我一起去了  我那时大概11岁
Took me with him. I was, like, 11.
他们比我大十岁左右
They were maybe 10 years older than me.
他们把我介绍给了那个人
They introduced us to the guy.
他的脸上  鼻子和脸颊下面
His face, underneath his nose and cheeks,
布满了伤疤
scarred.
整晚都在做奇怪的表情
Gave me funny looks all night.
每次我瞥到他  他都在盯着我
Every time I glanced at him, staring at me.
有没有可能这个人也勒杜家的
Any chance this man with the scars was another Ledoux?
不  我不知道  我觉得不是
No. I don't know. I don't think so.
第二天早上  他们宿醉未醒没法打猎
Next morning, men were too hung-over to hunt.
我和爸爸回了家
Pop and I went home.
你之后还有见过那个有伤疤的人吗
You, uh, ever see him again, guy with the scars?
再也没有
Never again.
见过我会记得的
I'd remember.
操  我不喜欢这个地方
Fuck, I don't like this place.
所有东西生长的方向都不对
Nothing grows in the right direction.
这个女人是怎么查到的
Where'd this woman come from?
税务记录
Tax records.
从塔特尔的爸爸那儿领取薪水
Drew a paycheck from Tuttle's father.
佣人那类的性质
Uh, some kind of domestic.
你怎么找到她的
How'd you find her?
我找到了40年到59年间的联邦所得税记录
Well, had to get federal income tax records from '40 to '59.
发现社保号和90年代末
I matched Social with a credit check run
一次信用核查相匹配
in the late nineties
当时是为了在亚历山大第八区租房
for Section-8 housing in Alexandria.
做得好
Good job.
看看你
Look at you. Heh!
一个酒保给了我好高的赞扬
High praise from a bartender.
条子
Cops.
她很容易累
She gets tired easy,
特别是像现在这么热
'specially hot as it is.
我不知道你们要干什么
Now, I don't understand what this is about.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们是私家侦探  受人雇佣前来
We're private investigators, hired to do, uh,
调查祖上的信息
ancestral research.
沿海的矿权问题
M-mineral rights along the coast.
我从来没见过塔特尔家的人  但我听过传言
I never knew them Tuttle people, but I heard stories.
算了吧  谢谢
No, thank you.
你觉得她可能从中赚到点钱吗
You think she might get some money out this?
很有可能
Uh, quite possible.
取决于我们能查出些什么
Depends on what we find out.
德洛丽丝女士
Miss Delores?
你给山姆·塔特尔先生工作了19年  对吗
You worked for Mr. Sam Tuttle 19 years, right?
是的
Yes.
在伊拉斯
Erath.
然后是薛夫波特
Then Shreveport.
那你认识他的儿子  比利·李  对吗
So you knew his son, Billy Lee, right?
他的堂兄  埃迪
A cousin, Eddie?
小男孩们  我记得
Little boys, mm-hmm. I remember.
远亲呢
What about extended family?
有没有堂兄之类的  跟男孩们比较熟的
Cousins, you know, that might have been close to the boys?
那时候的家族比现在庞大的多
Those days, families were bigger.
哥哥弟弟表亲堂亲  孩子们到处乱跑
Oh, all sorts of brothers, cousins, kids just running around.
山姆·塔特尔
Did, uh, Sam Tuttle have
有没有什么私生子
kids outside his marriage that you know about?
你该知道的
Hmm! Don't you know it.
现如今  人们独享自己的东西
Now, people kept their own back then.
男人的房子就是他自己的
I mean, a man's house was his own.
山姆先生呢
Mr. Sam?
他有很多孩子
He had lots of children.
性格迥异
All types.
他没对任何女人动过心
He didn't like a woman--
一旦女人和他发生了关系
See, once she had it done to her,
春宵一刻后  他就拔屌无情
he didn't like them but that one time.
绝不动心
Not after that.
在所有这些东奔西跑的孩子们中
Hmm, and out of all these kids running around,
有没有个孩子
you remember one that maybe had scars
脸下边可能有道疤
all across the bottom of his face?
那是山姆先生的孙子吧
I--I think that was Mr. Sam's grandchild.
那是他爸爸弄的  可怜的孩子
His daddy did that to him, that poor boy.
我觉得那孩子是柴尔德里斯家的人
I -- I think that child was a -- a Childress
菲  他是勒布家的还是柴尔德里斯家的
or what, Fi, he was a LeBeau or a Childress?
山姆先生其他家人的孩子吗
From Mr. Sam's other family?
我不该和你说这个的
I shouldn't be talking to you about this.
没关系的
That's OK.
徳洛丽斯小姐
Miss Delores.
能帮我确认件事吗  一件事
Could you have a look at something for me? One thing.
一眼就行  看您能不能认出来
Just have a look. See if you recognize it.
你知道卡寇莎
You know Carcosa?
那是什么
What is it?
他会吞噬时间
Him who eats time.
他的长袍
Him robes...
像一阵风  只闻其声不见其人
it's a wind of invisible voices.
什么矿权  你们到底在干嘛
Mineral rights, my ass. What you all doing?
庆祝
Rejoice.
死亡不是尽头
Death is not the end.
-庆祝  -你们得离开了  立刻
- Rejoice. - You need to leave, now.
-死亡不是尽头  -你们得离开了
- Death is not the end. - You need to leave.
你知道卡寇莎
You know Carcosa?
庆祝
You rejoice.
卡寇莎
Carcosa.
家里其余的人都不太和徳洛丽斯阿姨说话
Rest of the family, they don't really talk to Aunt D.
她疯了
She crazy.
痴呆
Dementia.
她从没过过好日子
She never had any kind of good life,
大部分时候  她都意识混乱
but most days, she can't even make sense.
是吗  我觉得她的意思很清楚
Yeah? She sure made sense to me.
那你值得担忧了  先生
That should worry you, mister.
真希望那个老太太是错的
Sure hope that old lady was wrong.
关于什么
About what?
死亡并不是尽头
About death not being the end of it.
我又调查了下玛丽·方特诺特
Did some backtracking on the Marie Fontenot stuff.
找到了几份以前的文件
Got some old sheets.
治安官签了"错报"
Sheriff signed off on the "Report made in error,"
但他并没有投诉她
but he didn't take the original complaint on her.
代理治安官投诉得
Deputy did.
你知道是谁吗
Got a name?
你肯定无法相信
You ain't gonna believe this shit.
史蒂夫·杰瑞西
Steve Geraci.
所以我复核了一次
So I did some double-checking.
当刑事调查员以前
Before CID,
他在梵米伦教区当治安官
he was with Vermillion Parish Sheriff's.
伊拉斯是他的辖区
Erath was his beat.
既然有人盖住了这件事
If it got covered up,
那史蒂夫可能知道些什么
Steve might know something.
我们95年问他的时候却什么都没说
Didn't say a fucking word when we asked about it in '95.
我一直都不喜欢那个混蛋
I never did like that cocksucker.
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
问题就在这里
Well, uh, this is the thing.
他来自伊比利亚
He's from Iberia originally.
不当刑事调查员以后  他就回家了
After CID, he went home.
他现在是伊比利亚教区的治安官
He's Sheriff of Iberia Parish.
操
Shit.
没错
Yeah.
拉斯特  在这个州
Rust, the only person can arrest the sheriff
能逮捕治安官的人  只有州长
in this state is the governor.
我们不是要去逮捕他  小马
Well, we ain't looking to arrest him, Marty,
只是找他谈谈话
just have a little chat.
他才不会来跟你谈话
Well, he ain't gonna talk with you.
我车里的电池和两跟跨接电缆可不这么认为
I got a car battery and two jumper cables argue different.
你最好别有那种想法
Don't even start with that shit.
那你有什么建议吗  小马
What do you recommend, Marty?
操  你为什么不去跟他谈谈
Well, fuck, why don't you talk to him?
你们俩不是一直看对方很对眼
You two always liked each other.
我只是比较会交际
Well, what can I say? I'm a people person.
那就跟他交际交际
Well, start with that, then.
拜托
Oh, come on.
放松一点  慢慢来
Just try to relax. Take your time.
进了
There you go.
好球
OK. Nice shot.
这距果岭有15码吗
What was that, 15 on the green?
我不知道
Ha ha ha! I don't know.
之前在电话里
Hey, you know, on the phone,
你提到过一个叫方特诺特的姑娘
you were saying something about that Fontenot girl.
-是啊  -你怎么会注意那个
- Yeah. - Why's that on your radar?
没什么  只是...
Oh, it's nothing. It's just, uh,
有个她的远房亲戚想知道她在哪儿
extended family wants a locate.
我当时没去记
I didn't remember at the time.
95年的时候
Back in '95,
我酗酒酗得很厉害
I was hitting the bottle a lot back then.
谁不是呢
Yeah, who wasn't?
已经20年了
20 years ago, you know.
我印象中
My recall,
孩子他妈还是单身
girl's mom was single,
被控吸毒
drug charges.
小女孩跑去跟生父一起过
Little girl went to live with her birth daddy, I think.
如果我没记错的话  就是这样
That is, if I'm remembering right.
第一次收到通知的时候
Uh, Mama didn't make a fuss after
妈妈没有大惊小怪  坦然接受了
the first notice, so she was fine with it.
你有直接和那家人谈过吗
And you talked to the family directly back then?
没有  泰德·柴尔德里斯去的
No. Ted Childress,
他是治安官  他认识他们
the sheriff. He knew them.
柴尔德里斯
Childress?
看好了
Now watch this.
喜欢吗
You like that?
一个南方佬那儿缴来的  他私藏大麻
Seized it off a good old boy, had a quarter-bag of weed.
你会爱死这国家的
Ooh. You got to love this country.
很高兴再见到你  伙计
Good to see you again, man.
我也一样
Good to see you.
对了
Hey, uh,
你的那个客户
that client you got,
在打听方特诺特女孩的那个
asking about the Fontenot girl.
你转告他们  我很乐意和他们聊聊
You let them know I'll be happy to talk to them.
是的  远房亲戚
Oh, yeah, distant relatives.
圣路易斯的  有点遗产问题要解决而已
St. Louis. Trying to settle a tiny inheritance.
没什么大不了的
Don't worry about it.
好的
Ok.
他们想谈谈的话  就告诉他们
Well, they want to talk, you let them know.
没问题  慢点开  治安官
Yeah. Don't go too fast, Sheriff.
那当然
Not me.
啥时候再一起玩
Let's do it again some time.
好啊  非常乐意
Yeah, I like that.
还是把跨接电缆准备好吧
Better get those jumper cables ready.
那狗娘养的在说谎
The motherfucker's lying.
拉斯特
Rust.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
扯淡
Bullshit.
我和小马谈过了
I talked to Marty.
我听说你也和警察谈过了
I hear you talked to the cops, too.
的确还有他们
Yes, them, too.
你好吗
How are you?
小马和你说了什么
What'd Marty tell you?
他想知道  警察问了我什么
He wanted to know what the police asked me about.
他说他在帮你事  就这么多
He said he was helping you with something. That's it.
你回来多久了
How long you been back?
听说你买了间大房子
Hear you got a big house.
小马说  女儿们都过得挺好
Marty says the girls are doing fine.
那样很好
That's good.
拉斯特
Rust,
告诉我  你们在做的事不会让他受到伤害
just tell me it's something that's not gonna get him hurt.
我没法给你这种保证
Well, I can't tell you that.
安全从来和我无缘
It never sat right with me,
现在也是一样  你这是在叫我说谎
and it doesn't now, you asking me to lie to you about him.
现在  快出去吧
Now, get on out of here.
这种破地方配不上你
You're classing the place up.
你为什么辞职  小马
Why'd you quit, Marty?
真正原因是什么  发生了什么
What's the real reason? What happened?
你不妨告诉我你回来的真正原因
You tell me why you come back, for real.
你先说
Mmm, you first.
你为什么辞职
Why'd you quit?
我看到些事
Well, I saw something.
婴儿
Baby.
一个混蛋想把孩子放进微波炉里烤干
Tweaker tried to dry the kid in a microwave.
看到他干的事  我就想
Saw that, what he'd done, and I thought...
再也不要了
never again.
我想  我再也不想看到
I thought I--I never want to look
那幅画面了
at anything like that anymore.
该你了
Your turn.
你回来干嘛
Why'd you, uh, why'd you come back?
就是这个
This.
在你能做其他事之前
Something I had to see to...
必须先解决某些事
Before getting on with something else.
我的生活就是
My life's been a circle
暴力和堕落的循环
of violence and degradation
从记事起就是如此
long as I can remember.
我要解除这个循环
I'm ready to tie it off.
船上见
See you on the boat.
那天之后我一直在想
After the other day, I was thinking,
为什么不经常去看看史蒂夫和孩子们
"Why don't I see Steve and the boys more?"
有一段时间没来这个营地了
Ain't been out to my camp in a while.
你知道  如果我一年里不来这里
You know, if I don't get out here
三四次
3, 4 times a year...
我就要崩溃了
I'm a basket case.
是啊是啊
I hear ya.
我最爱有一个
I do love a reason to drink beer
早上喝酒的正当理由了
first thing in the morning.
我说史蒂夫
Say, Steve,
我一直想问
I been wanting to ask,
你知道  那个方特诺特女孩
you know that Fontenot girl?
记得吗  跟他爸爸走掉的那个
Remember, going off with her daddy?
我不太明白
I--I just wasn't clear.
你是确实知道
Was it you knew for a fact
她跟她爸爸一起走了
that she went with her daddy,
还是有人跟你这么说得
or somebody told you that that's what happened?
那家人跟柴尔德里斯治安官谈过
The family talked to Sheriff Childress.
治安官认识他们
The girl's aunt and uncle,
就是女孩的姑姑和叔叔
he knew them.
他们是什么人
Who were they?
我开始觉得  这并不是一个
Starting to think this wasn't just
老朋友的友好邀请了
a friendly invitation from an old pal, huh?
当然是老朋友的友好邀请
It's definitely that.
这么说吧
Well, then try this, then.
我把能想起来的全说了
I said all I remember about the girl.
来好好享受一下  别再问了
Let's just have a good time, and don't ask again.
-我完全同意  -好吧
- I'm with you 150% on that. - All right.
问题是  史蒂夫
Thing is, Steve...
我不会再问你
I ain't gonna ask you.
他会
He is.
换做是我可不会这么做  史蒂夫
No, I wouldn't if I was you, Steve.
你现在可不在你的辖区  治安官
You're out of your jurisdiction, Sheriff.
你知道我现在是谁吗  混蛋
You realize who I am now, you assholes?
知道  不知道也不会来
Yeah, I wouldn't be here if I didn't.
小马
Marty.
别看我  我从来都控制不了他
Don't look at me. I ain't never been able to control him.
进来
Come on.
等这事完了看我怎么收拾你
But you're done after this.
我会把你丢到安哥拉  用胡桃钳撕烂你屁股
I'll have boss crackers splitting your ass in Angola.
我们会聊到那事的
Yeah, we'll talk about that,
还有些其他事
and some other things.
进来
Come on.
科尔说的那个教堂应该就在这儿
That church Cohle talked about's supposed to be right here.
-我们迷路了  -我们没有迷路
- We're lost. - We're not lost.
我们方向正确  在往南走
We're going in the right direction. We're heading south.
这样能走到49号公路吗
And that's gonna head us to 49?
我们不是在找49号公路
No, we're not looking for the 49.
是在找教堂
We're looking for the church.
我知道在找教堂  但什么教堂都没找到
I know we're looking for the church; we ain't got to no church.
连像教堂的东西都看不见
Ain't seen nothing that even resemble no church.
连个问句话的人都找不到
Ain't nobody out here to even ask where anything is.
看见东西告诉我
Let me know when you see something.
没什么可看见的
There ain't nothing to see.
你好  长官
Yes, sir?
你知道附近有个小教堂吗
You know there's a little church around here?
挺旧的  牧师是黑人
Pretty old? Black minister?
你一定是指生命之子  长官
You must mean Son of Life, sir.
那地方关了
That place shut down.
我记得是05年关的吧  飓风之后
'05, I think, just after all them hurricanes.
你住在附近吗
You live around here?
不  长官  我在圣马丁住
No, sir. I live in St. Martin.
签到了教区的工作合同
Got a parish contract.
照管墓地
Take care of some cemeteries,
和公立学校
public schools.
好的  谢谢
All right. Thanks.
你知道从这儿怎么上49号公路吗
Hey, you know how to get to 49 from here?
当然
Sure.
走半公里  能看见一个左转路口
About a half-mile, you'll see a left.
1435大道
Pr 1435.
走那条路
Take that.
大概开11公里
About...7 miles of fields.
不到克劳利  就能上49号公路
You'll hit 49 before Crowley.
你对这里的路挺清楚的嘛
Know your way around, huh?
是的  老大
Oh, yeah, boss.
-我了解整条海岸  我家  -谢谢
- I know the whole coast. My family-- - Thanks.
我家族在这里生活很长  很长时间了
My family's been here a long, long time.